Allison McCulloch's vegan film critiques hit like a sledgehammer to Hollywood's casual animal exploitation.
Her vegan alerts on Letterboxd dissect everything from fur coats to background steak dinners,
forcing viewers to confront the invisible violence in mundane details.
I think her approach is fascinating, not just as activism but as a new lens for media literacy.
When she calls out Craven the hunter's dissonance, saving lions while eating steak,
it exposes how thoughtlessly scripts normalize animal consumption.
Her system reminds me of peeling an onion.
Each layer reveals hidden ethical contradictions.
Take Nosferatu getting docked for horse carriages and vampire symbolism.
It's not about literal harm, but the cultural baggage of animal subjugation.
McCulloch's reviews aren't just warnings.
They're blueprints for reimagining storytelling without defaulting to exploitation.
But here's my hot take.
This isn't about policing art.
It's about accountability.
If a character's leather jacket or omelet breakfast isn't essential to the plot, why include it?
McCulloch's work pressures creators to ask that question, and maybe swap cliches for conscious choices.
Still, I wonder, does this hyper-awareness risk reducing films to checklists?
Either way, she's shifting the conversation.
Stay tuned, give this video a like, and consider subscribing.